Priyadarshini K

Research Scientist, Sony Research priyadarshini.kumari@sony.com https://priyadarshini-k.com/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Multimodal learning, Data-efficient machine learning, Distributed machine learning, Active and transfer learning

My research is motivated by the goal of *modeling* and *synthesizing* a multimodal system using ML tools. To achieve data efficiency, I also work on developing *active and transfer learning* algorithms for data-scarce domains, including biomedical, computer vision, natural language processing, and AI for science applications.

APPOINTMENTS

- Research Scientist, Sony Research	Sept 2021 - present
- Project Research Engineer, IIT Bombay	Aug 2015 - Dec 2015
- Risk Analyst, CitiCorp Service India Ltd, Pune	Jul 2013 - Oct 2014
- Research Associate, IIT Bombay	Jul 2010 - Jun 2013

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Technology Bombay

2016 - 2021

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Thesis: Label-Efficient Distance Metric Learning

Advisor: Prof. Subhasis Chaudhuri and Prof. Siddhartha Chaudhuri

Indian Institute of Technology Bombay

2011 - 2013

Masters in Electrical Engineering

Thesis: Multimodal Rendering of 3D Objects at Different Scales

AWARDS AND HONORS

- TCS Ph.D. Research Fellowship for 4 years (2016 2019)
- Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Finalist, 2019
- Department Excellence in Teaching Assistantship (TA), 2018
- Recipient of MHRD PhD Fellowship 2016
- Recipient of MHRD Post-Graduate fellowship 2011

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Uchenna Akujuobi, **Priyadarshini K**, Jihun Choi, Samy Badreddine, Kana Maruyama, Sucheendra K. Palaniappan and Tarek R. Besold. Using the dynamics of discovery: A temporal graph-based hierarchical approach to automated hypothesis generation (under submission)
- 2. Daniel Shin, Gao Pei, **Priyadarshini K**, and Tarek Besold. Optimizing Learning Across Multimodal Transfer Features for Modeling Olfactory Perception, SIGKDD Multimodal Workshop 2023
- 3. **Priyadarshini K** and Michael Spranger. Perceptual metrics for odorants: learning from non-expert similarity feedback using machine learning (under submission)
- 4. Tanoy Debnath, Samy Badreddine, **Priyadarshini K** and Michael Spranger. Comparing molecular representations, e-nose signals, and other featurization, for learning to smell aroma molecules, PLOS One, 2023
- 5. **Priyadarshini K** and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Enhancing Haptic Distinguishability of Surface Materials with Boosting Technique. IEEE Haptics Symposium 2022
- 6. **Priyadarshini K**, Siddhartha Chaudhuri, Vivek Borkar and Subhasis Chaudhuri. A unified batch selection policy for active metric learning, ECML-PKDD, 2021
- 7. **Priyadarshini K**, Ritesh Goru, Siddhartha Chaudhuri, and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Batch Decorrelation for Active Metric Learning, IJCAI-PRICAI, 2020.
- 8. **Priyadarshini K**, Siddhartha Chaudhuri, and Subhasis Chaudhuri. PerceptNet: Learning Perceptual Similarity of Haptic Textures in Presence of Unorderable Triplets. IEEE World Haptics Conference (IEEE WHC), 2019.
- 9. **Priyadarshini K** and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Haptic Rendering of Thin, Deformable Objects with Spatially Varying Stiffness. EuroHaptics, 2016.
- 10. Praseedha K., Sreeni K., **Priyadarshini K**, Subhasis Chaudhuri. Combined Hapto-Visual and Auditory Rendering of Cultural Heritage Objects. Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) e-Heritage Workshop, 2014.
- 11. **Priyadarshini K**, Sreeni K.G. and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Scalable Rendering of Variable Density Point Cloud Data. IEEE World Haptics Conference (IEEE WHC), 2013.
- 12. Sreeni K.G., **Priyadarshini K**, A.K. Praseedha and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Haptic Rendering of Cultural Heritage Objects at Different Scales. EuroHaptics, 2012.

BOOK CHAPTER

Subhasis Chaudhuri and **Priyadarshini Kumari**. Cultural Heritage Object: Bringing Them Alive Through Virtual Touch, *Diqital Hampi: Preserving Indian Cultural Heritage*, Springer, 2018.

MASTERS THESIS

Multimodal Rendering of 3D Objects at Different Scales

- Summary: Developed a multimodal rendering technique to synthesize a combined *hapto-visual-auditory* perceptual experience of interaction with 3D model of objects. The goal of this project was to provide access to the heritage objects to visually-impaired people.
- **Domains involved:** Image Processing, Computer Graphics, Computer Vision, Haptic Signal Processing.

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Senior program chair for WiML un-workshop @ ICML 2023
- Area chair for WiML workshop @ NeurIPS 2022
- Session chair for ECML-PKDD 2021
- Reviewer: IEEE World Haptic Conference, ECML-PKDD, IJCAI, Eurohaptics, ISMAR

TEACHING

Wavelet [Spring 2020] Computer Vision [Spring 2016, Spring 2017, Spring 2018] Statistical Signal Analysis Digital Signal Processing [Spring 2019] Signals and System [Fall 2017, Fall 2018] Communication Lab

[Fall 2019]

[Fall 2016]